[
  {
    "question": "1. What is the difference between val and var in Kotlin?",
    "answer1": "Variables declared with val are final, those with var are not.",
    "answer2": "Variable declared with val can only access const members",
    "answer3": "Variables declared with var are final, those with val are not.",
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "2. What does a data class not offer?",
    "answer1": "Automatic conversion from/to JSON",
    "answer2": "Auto-generated toString() method",
    "answer3": "A generated copy(...) method, to create copies of instances",
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Which of these targets does Kotlin currently not support",
    "answer1": "LLVM",
    "answer2": ".NET CLR",
    "answer3": "JVM",
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "4. What are Kotlin coroutines",
    "answer1": "They provide asynchronous code without thread blocking",
    "answer2": "That's how the automatically generated methods hashCode() and equals() is data classes are called",
    "answer3": "These are functions which accept other functions as arguments or return them",
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "5. What is the correct way to declare a variable of integer type in Kotlin",
    "answer1": "int i = 42",
    "answer2": "var i : int = 42",
    "answer3": "var i : Int 42",
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What is the correct syntax to convert the String \"42\" to a Long in Kotlin",
    "answer1": "val l: Long = \"42\".toLong()",
    "answer2": "val l: Long = (Long)\"42\"",
    "answer3": "val l: Long = <Long>\"42\"",
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "7. Does Kotlin have primitive data types, such as int, long, float?",
    "answer1": "No, Kotlin does not have nor use primitive data types",
    "answer2": "Yes, Kotlin is similar to Java in this respect",
    "answer3": "No, not at language level. But the Kotlin compiler makes use of JVM primitive for best performance",
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "8. Android applications must be signed",
    "answer1": "After they are installed",
    "answer2": "Before they are installed",
    "answer3": "Within tow weeks of installation",
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "9. What does the .APK extension stand for",
    "answer1": "Application Package",
    "answer2": "Application Program Kit",
    "answer3": "Android Proprietary Kit",
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "10. Which is a valid function declaration in Kotlin?",
    "answer1": "int sum(int a, int b)",
    "answer2": "fun sum(a: Int, b: Int): Int",
    "answer3": "fun sum(a: Int, b: Int)",
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "11. What does the !! operator do?",
    "answer1": "It converts any value to a non-null type and throws an exception if the value is in fact null",
    "answer2": "It's the modulo operator in Kotlin, similar to Java's %",
    "answer3": "it compares two values for identify rather than equality",
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "12. What is the key difference between Iterable<T> and Sequence<T> in Kotlin?",
    "answer1": "Sequences are processed sequentially, Iterables in parallel (multithreaded)",
    "answer2": "Sequences are processed lazily, Iterables eagerly",
    "answer3": "There is no difference, as Sequence<T> is Kotlin's term for Iterable<T>",
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "13. Under which license is Kotlin available?",
    "answer1": "MIT",
    "answer2": "Apache 2",
    "answer3": "GPL",
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "14. An open source standalone database",
    "answer1": "SQLite",
    "answer2": "BackupHelper",
    "answer3": "NetworkInfo",
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "question": "15. When Developing for the Android OS, Java byte code is compiled into what?",
    "answer1": "Java Source Code",
    "answer2": "Dalvik Application Code",
    "answer3": "Dalvik Byte Code",
    "correctAnswer": 2
  }
]